# Joyce H. Rogina

Basking Ridge, NJ 07920 http://www.linkedin.com/in/JoyceRoginaEsq (732) 735-3053 joyce.rogina@gmail.com

# **Executive Summary**

Business-minded associate general counsel, chief privacy officer and cross-functional leader with data governance experience and an extensive background identifying critical success factors then designing, implementing, measuring and enhancing strategic, large-scale programs in legal, corporate and entrepreneurial roles over the course of four decades to meet risk management, operational efficiency and revenue goals. Recognized as a proactive self-starter with outstanding communication skills, broad data protection and policy, technology and commercial law experience, and a commitment to professional ethics and integrity

# **Professional Experience**

# BARNES & NOBLE EDUCATION, INC., Basking Ridge, NJ

Jan 2016 - Present

Barnes & Noble Education, spun off in 2015 as a publicly traded company from the neighborhood bookstore chain, is one of the largest contract operators of institutional bookstores, managing over 1,200 stores serving six million students delivering educational content, products, services and emblematic merchandise

#### Vice President, Chief Privacy Officer, Associate General Counsel

- Advise senior leadership, the board of directors and other internal clients on worldwide privacy law matters, including GDPR and CCPA, as amended, related SEC and other regulatory matters, incident response, data retention, risk mitigation, marketing and advertising
- Design, implement, iterate and improve an enterprise-wide data privacy compliance program, including drafting internal policies and external notices, to help mitigate risk and ensure the protection of personal information and company confidential information from unauthorized access or processing
- Draft, review and negotiate commercial agreements, including data processing agreements, purchase agreements (as seller and as buyer), strategic partnerships, master service agreements, licensing agreements, SaaS and other technology transactions to help enable the company's digital transformation
- Partner with the CIO and the CISO, demonstrating increasing levels of responsibility and autonomy with three promotions in the first four years with the company, reporting directly to the CLO

# CELLCO PARTNERSHIP D/B/A VERIZON WIRELESS, Basking Ridge, NJ

2005 - 2015

Founded in 2000, Verizon Wireless is now wholly owned by Verizon Communications Inc., one of the world's leading providers of communications, technology, information and entertainment products and services to consumers, businesses and government entities

# **Contracts and Government Policy Strategist, Lead Negotiator**

2013 - 2015

 Managed cross-functional teams to develop and execute negotiation strategies in support of "new money" product launches in regulated industries, including healthcare and education, in order to assess market appetite and validate business models, achieving the company's highest performance rating

# Partnership Manager, Lead Negotiator

2007 - 2013

 Cultivated relationships at all organizational levels and closed complex contracts, including licensing, service level and outsourcing agreements, with strategic business partners, including Qualcomm, Intel and Asurion with deals driving an estimated \$1 billion in incremental revenue and an estimated \$400 million in cost avoidance

# **Sales and Distribution Contracts Attorney**

2005 - 2007

- In-house counsel and privacy law SME responsible for drafting and negotiating commercial contracts with sophisticated corporate customers, while supporting the department's efforts to increase operational efficiency and train field sales personnel
- Recruited internally out of Legal by a Verizon Wireless executive to manage its Qualcomm relationship and restructure a 2001 contract hindering Verizon Wireless' revenue growth (after four previously unsuccessful attempts by others to close a new deal)

LEXISNEXIS GROUP, New York, NY; Philadelphia, PA

2001 – 2004

various data analytic products serving customers in 150 countries

## **Corporate Counsel Consultant**

 Lead attorney and expert researcher that serviced top corporate legal clients, pre- and post-sales, including developing and teaching programs resulting in the issuance of 200 state-approved Continuing Legal Education credits for customers in intellectual property, ethics and compliance

### LOWENSTEIN SANDLER LLP, Roseland, NJ

1999 – 2000, 1994 – 1996

Lowenstein Sandler is a national law firm with over 350 attorneys in five states representing clients in every segment of the global economy and placing 99<sup>th</sup> on The American Lawyer's 2023 Am Law 200 ranking

### **Corporate Associate**

• Fifth-year corporate associate with a business law practice focused on securities regulation, sophisticated investment management vehicles, commercial transactions, due diligence and start-up businesses

#### WORLDSCAPE INC., Bridgewater, NJ

1996 - 1999

WorldScape was a closely held technology start-up, which ultimately became a U.S. Department of Defense contractor, offering patented immersive imaging technology

#### Co-Founder, Vice President

• Entrepreneur who wrote the initial business plan, conducted business development, negotiated contracts and managed outside patent and corporate counsel for a technology start-up

#### **HEWLETT-PACKARD COMPANY**, Orlando, FL; New York, NY

The centerpiece of Silicon Valley in the late 1970s, HP was a hardware manufacturer, provider of software solutions and a major brand in the history of computers and computer-related products

#### **Business Development Manager**

1989 - 1991

 Senior technical sales professional requested by the leadership team to pioneer a new role to initiate and manage C-suite level relationships to uncover strategic opportunities with select Fortune 50 companies that had not previously conducted business with HP; offered leave of absence by HP management to attend NYU Law

#### **Major Account Manager**

1983 - 1989

 Technical sales professional that identified and drove an estimated \$2 million in sales of computer systems to support NASA and the government contractors affiliated with the Kennedy Space Center, FL, after previously doubling sales in an exclusive New York Area sales territory

### **Education**

Juris Doctorate – Corporate and transactional law focus NEW YORK UNIVERSITY SCHOOL OF LAW, New York, NY

1994

**Bachelor of Arts with Highest Honors** – Computer Applications (coding) and Psychology (industrial focus) **UNIVERSITY OF NOTRE DAME**, South Bend, IN 1984

 Academic scholarship recipient; first generation college student; excelled at coding in COBOL, Fortran and other compiled languages; Dean's List eight of eight semesters; undergraduate research published in a UK journal

#### **Certification, Licensure and Publication**

- 2021 International Association of Privacy Professionals CIPP/US
- 1994 Bar Admissions New Jersey (active) and Pennsylvania
- Stephan Arndt, Joan Feltes and Joyce Hanak [Rogina] (1983) Secretarial attitudes towards word processors as a function of familiarity and locus of control, Behaviour & Information Technology, 2:1, 17-22, DOI: 10.1080/01449298308914466